(ｶﾞﾗｽの割れる音)
なおさらです｡
(みんな)うわっ!!
(陸奥)これは…!?
(青木)して そちらは…？
(陸奥)頭は所用じゃ｡
(青木)もちろんでございます｡
(陸奥)どうやら
時間どおりのようじゃのぅ｡
(青木)坂本様は
いらっしゃらないので？
(青木)我らの求める品を
お持ちいただけるとなれば➡
(青木)な なんだ!?
(隊士)何してる 早く扉を開けろ!!
信用第一が 我ら青木商会の
ﾓｯﾄｰでございます｡
それより持ってきたのか？
は… こちらになります｡
(陸奥)注文の品 ２ﾀﾞｰｽじゃ｡
確認するぜよ｡
♪♪～
(青木)う… な ない！ 金が!!
(隊士)商品が… なくなっている!!
It looks like you're on time.
(陸奥)やられた…｡
Of course. "Trust is No.1" is Aoki and Co.'s motto.
It holds even truer if you have what we want...
Sakamoto-sama isn't here?
Our boss had something to attend to. Anyway, did you bring it?
Yes. It's over here.
Now what about you?
Two dozen units of what you ordered. You can verify it yourself.
W-What's this?!
W-What's going on?!
What are you doing?! Open the doors immediately!
T-The money! It's gone!!
What?! The goods are gone.
We've been had...
[Q: Who are the guys that appeared in the opening sequence?]
[Tatsuma Sakamoto (left), Mutsu (right)]
[Sorachi-sensei, happy birthday one day early. We'll really go "there" this time.]
["When Looking For Things You've Lost, Remember What You Were Doing On The Day You Lost It"]
Anyway, the goods and the money were stolen.
というわけで 積み荷も金も
奪われてしまったきに➡
頭といえば 地球に着くなり➡
When we landed on Earth, our boss wandered off and went missing.
ﾌﾗｯと外に出てったきり
行方不明じゃ｡
おまん なんとかするぜよ｡
You guys, go do something about it.
Do something? Sympathize with you?
(銀時)なんとかって 同情か？
なぐさめてほしいのか？
Do you want me to make you feel better? You want me to say some kind words?
優しい言葉を かけてほしいのか？
(神楽)違うよ銀ちゃん 罵倒よ｡
No, Gin-chan. She wants you to insult her.
汚い言葉を 浴びせかけて
もらいたいｱﾙよ きっと｡
She wants you to shower her with bad words. I'm sure of it!
(新八)いや違うから｡
これって依頼だからさ たぶん｡
No, she doesn't. This is probably a request.
たぶんじゃないきに｡
立派な依頼じゃ｡
Not probably. It is a request.
依頼？
言っとくけど これ ﾋﾞｼﾞﾈｽだから｡
A request? Let me remind you that this is a business.
知り合いだからって
割引なんてしねえよ おい｡
I won't give you a discount just because we know each other.
(陸奥)金なら ある｡
I have money.
So what does the job entail?
で 依頼内容は？
切り替え 早っ｡
What a quick change in his attitude!
これを見るぜよ｡
あ…｡
Take a look at this.
Okay...
You'll get paid after you finish the job.
報酬は 仕事が終わってからぜよ｡
ﾁｪｯ…｡
Bummer...
これは？
(陸奥)奪われた積み荷じゃ｡
What's this?
These are the stolen cargo.
ﾅｼｵﾅﾙ星の特殊鉱物より
抽出された物質で作られた➡
Two dozen Yakuman batteries made from a material extracted
役満感電血 ２ﾀﾞｰｽじゃ｡
from a special mineral from the planet Nasional.
感電血？
(陸奥)ただの感電血じゃないきに｡
Batteries?
They're not ordinary batteries.
[Battery]
(陸奥)これ１本で 宇宙戦艦の➡
One of these is strong enough to power an entire space battleship.
動力すべてを
まかなえる 優れもんじゃ｡
What do you plan to do with twenty of them?
そんなもん
20個も どうするつもりだ？
24個ですよ 銀さん｡
It's twenty-four, Gin-san.
おまんらに やってもらうのは
感電血と金の回収➡
I want you to retrieve the batteries and the money, find our boss, and return them all to me.
及び 頭を見つけ出して ﾜｼの前に
連れてくることじゃきに｡
言うのは簡単だがよ
手がかりが少なすぎやしねえか？
It's easy to say that, but there's hardly any leads to go on?
江戸ったって広いんだ｡
Edo is big. It's like trying to find a specific grain of sand in a beach.
こりゃあ 砂浜から特定の砂粒
見つけ出すようなもんだぜ｡
They just keep on coming. What is it this time?
次から次へと… 今度はなんだ？
あるなら まとめて出すよろし｡
If you have something to show us, do it all at once.
The Pleasure Support Club has no idea where they might be.
(陸奥)快援隊に心当たりはない｡
何か探りたいなら
取引相手のところへ行くぜよ｡
[Aoki and Co.]
[CEO, President Aoki]
If you're going to ask questions, go to the people we were conducting our trade with.
(陸奥)あっ そうそう… それと｡
(銀時たち)んっ… あ!?
Oh yes. Also...
If you're ever in trouble, use this.
困ったときは これを使うぜよ｡
でもって 頭 見つけたら まずは➡
And when you find our boss, kick him in the balls for me.
ふぐり 蹴っ飛ばしといてくれ｡
銀さん まずは その➡
Gin-san, you're going to talk to the company that was part of the trade, aren't you?
取引相手のところに
行くんですよね？
No...
いいや｡
じゃあ どこ行くｱﾙか？
Then where are you going?
I'm going to go kick someone in the balls.
ふぐり蹴り飛ばしに｡
ふぐり？
The balls?
あぁ 坂本さんのことですね｡
Yeah. Sakamoto-san, right? Do you have any idea where he is?
どこにいるか
見当がついてるんですか？
Pretty much.
まぁな｡
やっぱり あれですかね➡
He's the leader of the Pleasure Support Club,
快援隊の隊長なわけですから
責任を感じて➡
so do you think he's gone off to investigate this himself because he feels responsible?
独自に調査とか
してるんですかね？
I told you before, didn't I? His head is empty.
前にも言ったよな？
ｱｲﾂ 頭 空だから｡
Oryo-chan, please marry me!
(坂本)おりょうちゃ～ん
結婚してくれ～!!
(おりょう)ﾉｰｾﾝｷｭｰ!!
No, thank you!
(神楽)本当ｱﾙ 空だったｱﾙ｡
You're right. It really is empty.
ｵﾚが蹴るまでもなかったな｡
ｱﾊﾊﾊ…｡
Looks like I won't have to kick him...
(坂本)ｲﾀﾀﾀ！ ちぎれる ちぎれる｡
Ow-ow-ow-ow-ow-ow!
You're pulling it out! You're pulling it out! You're pulling it out!
やめて やめてってば 金時！
S-S-S-Stop! Stop, Kintoki!
[Note: In Japanese, "gin" means "silver" and "kin" means "gold."]
How many times do I need to tell you?!
何度も言わせんじゃねえよ
金じゃなくて銀だから｡
It's not "kin," it's "gin." How long are you going to keep doing that?
いつまで引っ張るつもり？
そのﾈﾀ｡
All right! I get it! Let go!
わかった… わかったぜよ
だから離すぜよ｡
ｲﾃﾃ… で ﾜｼに何の用じゃ？ 金時｡
So what do you want with me, Kintoki?
って なに聞いてんの ｵﾒｴ!!
Were you listening to me?
待ってください 銀さん！
こんなことやってたら➡
Wait, Gin-san! We won't get anywhere if we keep at this!
いつまでも
話が先に進みませんよ!!
金でも銀でも
どっちでもいいｱﾙよ｡
It doesn't matter if he says "kin" or "gin."
This is important. It's going to appear on the test!
ここ 大事なところだからさ！
ﾃｽﾄに出るからっ!!
If someone called your name, wouldn't you hate it if they said,
ｵﾒｴも名前呼ばれるとき
｢神楽坂ちゃ～ん ｱｯﾊｯﾊ～｣➡
"Kagurazaka-chan. Ahahahaha"? You'd hate it, wouldn't you?
[Note: Kagurazaka is in Shinjuku district in Tokyo.]
とか言われたら
ｲﾔだろう？ ｲﾔだろ？
That really pisses me off.
なんか すっごい ﾑｶつくね！
I didn't say that. I didn't say...
I'm going to kill you!!
ｵﾚが言ったんじゃない！
(坂本)あの～｡
I may not look it, but I'm rather busy.
こう見えても ﾜｼは忙しいきに｡
用がないなら➡
If you don't have any business with me, can I go?
帰らせてもらってもいいかの？
ｱﾊﾊﾊ…｡
(銀時たち)ﾃﾒｴのために
動いてんだよ こっちは!!
We're here because of you, you bastard!!
Huh? Batteries? I don't know about that...
はぁ 感電血？ 知らんなぁ｡
ｵﾒｴが盗まれたんじゃねえの？
They were stolen from you! Weren't they your company's cargo?!
お前んとこの
積み荷なんじゃねえの!?
ｱﾊﾊ… 細かいことは
陸奥に任せちょるからのぅ｡
I leave the little things to Mutsu.
There's no use asking me. I don't have any idea at all.
ﾜｼに言われても
皆目 見当もつかんぜよ｡ ｱﾊﾊ｡
Oh, the pretty lady over there...
わっ そこの
きれいな おねえちゃん➡
ﾜｼと遊ばんね？ ｱﾊﾊ…｡
Want to have some fun with me?
No, thank you!
(ｳｪｲﾄﾚｽ)ﾉｰｾﾝｷｭｰです｡
ｱﾊﾊ こりゃ まいったのぅ｡
That didn't go well...
でしたら 青木商会って
とこについて何か知りませんか？
Then do you know anything about Aoki and Co.?
Beats me. I don't know about little things.
さぁな… ﾜｼは細かいことは
よう わからんきに ﾊﾊﾊ…！
Anyway, Kintoki, we haven't seen each other in a while.
それより 金時!!
久しぶりの再会じゃ！
おりょうちゃんのところで
ﾊﾟｰｯとやるぜよ！
Let's party at Oryo's place.
銀ちゃん ｺｲﾂ また
振り出しに戻すつもりｱﾙよ｡
Gin-chan, he's trying to bring us back to where we started.
どこまでﾎﾞｹ通せば
気がすむんだよ ｵﾒｴは！
How long are you going to play village idiot with us?
ここが青木商会…｡
So this is Aoki and Co.
うまく 話が
聞けるといいんですけど｡
It would be nice if they'd talk to us.
そのために
ｺｲﾂを連れてきたんだ！
That's why we brought this guy.
Ladies, want to have some fun with me?
(坂本)おねえちゃんたち！
ﾜｼと遊ばない？
No, thank you.
(女の子)ﾉｰｾﾝｷｭｰ！
(坂本)ｱﾊﾊ… うわぁ!!
商売相手の社長がいんだ｡
何とかなんだろ！
The president of the company you were dealing with is here.
You can do something, right?
(坂本)ちょっと待って…
おねえちゃんたち！
W-Wait, ladies...
(青木)これは これは 坂本様…
このたびは お互い 災難でしたね｡
Well, well, Sakamoto-sama.
It's been quite terrible for both of us, hasn't it?
Let's get down to business.
さっそくですけど
襲ってきた相手に➡
Do you have any idea who might have attacked you?
心当たりはあるんですか？
(青木)さぁ…｡
Who knows? Our motto is "Trust is No.1."
我々は 信用第一を
ﾓｯﾄｰにしていますので…｡
他の人に恨まれるようなことは
していないと思うのですが…｡
I don't think we've done anything that would make anyone hold a grudge against us.
But someone attacked you specifically during your transaction.
だが 実際には取り引きの現場を➡
ﾋﾟﾝﾎﾟｲﾝﾄで
襲われてるわけじゃねえか｡
情報が前もって洩れてたとしか
思えねえがな｡
I can only speculate that information about the trade was leaked ahead of time.
The same goes for both of us. Don't forget that we were also victims.
(青木)それは
お互いさまでございます｡
こちらも被害者であることを
お忘れなく…｡
(青木)とはいえ こちらも現在➡
Even so, we're also investigating the incident at the moment.
事件については
調査中でございます｡
I'll let you know if we find something out.
何かわかれば
すぐに お知らせいたしますので｡
I just don't get it.
なんだかよぉ… まったく…｡
We haven't found a single clue since yesterday.
昨日から 何ひとつ 手がかりが
つかめてないんですけど…｡
(神楽)見つかったのは
役立たずの社長だけｱﾙ｡
All we found was a good-for-nothing president.
He's more like a plant manager than a president.
(神楽)やっぱり
社長より 工場長よ｡
なぁ 金時… ﾜｼはもう疲れたぜよ｡
Say, Kintoki, I'm tired already. Let's have some sake.
そろそろ酒にしようや ﾊﾊﾊ…！
なに言ってんですか！
What are you saying? Your Pleasure Support Club asked us to do this.
坂本さんの
快援隊の依頼なんですよ｡
依頼主の坂本さんが
足ひっぱって どうするんですか！
What's the point in slowing us down? Right, Gin-san?
ねぇ 銀さん｡
(坂本/銀時)ｱﾊﾊﾊ…！
I'll send the bill to Mutsu. Keep on drinking.
勘定は陸奥につけとくけ
ｶﾞﾝｶﾞﾝ飲め飲め！ ｱﾊﾊﾊ…!!
Is it all right to be doing this?
いいんですか？
こんなことしてて…｡
だって しようがないじゃん！
We've got no choice. The client wants us to drink!
依頼主が飲めって
言ってんだからよ～！
そうじゃ そうじゃ｡
That's right. Stop talking about silly things and drink!
お前も くだらんことばっか
言うちょらんで 飲め飲め！ ｱﾊﾊ｡
No. I'm a minor.
いや ﾎﾞｸ 未成年なんですけどね｡
If you can't drink, then eat.
飲めないなら 食べればいいｱﾙよ｡
いつまでも
応用力のないｶﾞｷだな お前｡
You'll never gain any practical skills by being a malnourished brat.
お茶漬け おかわりｱﾙ！
働けよな お前も｡
Another helping of o-chazuke!!
[Note: O-chazuke is rice with tea poured on it.]
You should do some work, too.
(坂本)今日は 祭りじゃき！
さぁ 飲め飲め!! ｱﾊﾊ…！
We're having a party today. Come on, drink, drink!
(坂本と銀時の笑い声)
(吐く音)
だから言ったじゃないですか！
I told you so.
What did you tell me, huh?
お前が 何を言ったんだ？ えっ？
(坂本)酒は飲んでも
飲まれるな的なことかのぅ ﾊﾊﾊ…｡
Something like, "If you drink sake, don't get drunk."
わかってるなら
最初から飲むなよな｡
Then you shouldn't have been drinking in the beginning.
(坂本)
それができりゃ 苦労はせんぜよ！
We wouldn't be suffering if we could, right, Kintoki?
なぁ 金時… ﾊﾊｯ ﾊﾊｯ…！
Sake is all about drinking and getting drunk over and over.
酒ってのは
飲んで飲まれての繰り返しだよ｡
それが人生ってﾔﾂさ…｡
That's what life is all about.
借金で首のまわらなくなった
博打打ちの言い訳と➡
That's no different from what a gambler who's over his head in debt would say.
なんら変わらないｱﾙな｡
つまりﾀﾞﾒ人間ってことか｡
In other words, they're hopeless human beings.
(新八/神楽)はぁ…｡
あ～あ…
結局 今日は ﾑﾀﾞ足でしたね｡
In the end, today was a complete waste.
そうでもねえみてえだぜ！
ん？
It doesn't look that way.
派手に動き回った甲斐が
あったみたいだな｡
It looks like it was worth making a lot of noise.
Kintoki, do you still remember?
金時 おまん 覚えちょるか？
忘れるわけねえだろ！
I'd never forget.
(坂本)ﾜｼの合図で動くぜよ！
あぁ…｡
We'll move on my signal.
Okay...
今ぜよ！
わかってらぁ!!
Now!
All right!
(２人)あぁ！
って何やってんですか～!?
What are you doing?!
(戦闘員たちの奇声)
うわ～ なんか来た～!!
Something's coming!!
Jeez.
ったく なまってんだから
引っ込んでろ！ ここは ｵﾚ様が!!
Your skills have gotten rusty. Stand back.
I'll handle this.
うおぉ～！
(奇声)
(着弾音)
辰馬…｡
Tatsuma...
I'm using this now...
これからは これぜよ！
(坂本)さぁ どうするきに…｡
What are you going to do now? If you move one step... Bang!
(坂本)一歩でも動けば ｽﾞﾄﾞﾝ！
(悲鳴)
If you leave quietly, I won't do anything to you.
おとなしく帰るなら
こっちも 手は出さんぜよ｡
(悲鳴)
すごい… 戦わずして
敵を追い払った…｡
Amazing. He drove the enemy away without fighting.
ﾍﾍｯ… ﾑﾀﾞなｹﾝｶは しちゃあかん！
We mustn't get into unnecessary fights.
勝っても負けても いいことなんて
ないきにな！ ﾊﾊﾊ…!!
Nothing good will happen whether we win or lose.
Hey...
って 何やってんの!? ｵﾒｴ！
What are you doing?!
せっかくの手がかり まるまる
逃がしてどうすんだよ このﾎﾞｹ！
You just let our lead escape, you moron!
B-But no one got hurt, so isn't it all right?
で… でも ｹｶﾞ人が
出なかったんですから➡
よかったじゃないですか！
ﾊﾞｶ言ってんじゃねえ!!
Don't be stupid! We're right back where we started!
これでまた 振り出しに
戻っちまったじゃねえか！
この役立たず！
役立たず!! 役立たず！
You good-for-nothing! Good-for-nothing! Good-for-nothing!!
(青木)あ… あの…｡
何だよ！
U-Umm...
What is it?!
(神楽)こっちは
今 取り込み中ｱﾙよ！
We're busy right now!
Oh...
あっ…｡
(２人)ん？
あなたは青木商会の…｡
You're from Aoki and Co.
Sorry to interrupt you earlier while you were busy.
先程は失礼いたしました
すみません お忙しいなか…｡
So what do you want?
で なんか用？
We're irritated right now,
こっちは 今 ｲﾗｲﾗしてるから➡
so if it's something frivolous, we're take out our frustrations on him.
くだらねえ用事だったら
ｺｲﾂに やつあたりすんぞ おい！
ご機嫌とりたいっていうんなら
ｺｼﾋｶﾘ10ｷﾛ 持ってくるよろし｡
If you want to make us feel better, bring us ten kilos of Koshihikari.
[Note: Koshihikari is a type of rice.]
なぜ さりげなく米を要求？
Why are you slipping in a demand for rice?
先程のお話で➡
I want you to hear about some information I obtained concerning what we discussed earlier.
お耳に入れておきたい情報が
ございまして…｡
情報？
(青木)私どもが➡
Information?
After conducting our internal investigation,
独自に調査を進めた結果➡
あの感電血を
欲しがっているという➡
we've discovered the identity of the organization that wanted those batteries.
ある組織を突き止めたのです｡
So which organization is it?
それで その組織とは？
It's called Evil Organization.
(青木)はい その名は 悪の組織｡
Evil Organization...what?
悪の組織… なに!?
It's an evil organization that's called "Evil Organization."
ですから 悪の組織という名の
悪の組織です｡
♪♪～
Evil Organization Ltd.
で？ これが その
なんとかいうﾔﾂのｱｼﾞﾄか？
So this is what's-their-name's... Hideout, huh?
悪の組織ですよ｡
It's "Evil Organization."
It's written in big letters on their sign.
看板に でかく書いてｱﾙよ｡
有限会社じゃと｡ ｱﾊﾊﾊﾊﾊ！
They're a corporation?
しかも
こんな 野っ原の真ん中に…｡
And they're in the middle of a field... What should we do, Gin-san?
どうしますか？ 銀さん｡
Don't ask me. It's tiring for me to use up my energy if I don't have to.
どう？ って 言われてもなぁ…｡
ﾑﾀﾞな体力 消費するのも疲れるし｡
Anyway, let's sneak in from the back.
とりあえず
裏口から 忍び込んでみっか…｡
Hello! I'm from Pleasure Support Club!
(坂本)こんにちは～！
快援隊です…｡
We just talked about this! Don't do that!
って 言ってるそばから
それかい!!
三河屋みたいに 気軽ｱﾙ！
He's as flippant as Mikawaya, our neighborhood liquor store!
そんなに ﾎﾞｹたいのか！ あぁ!?
Do you want to act stupid that badly? Do you?!
そこまでして ﾎﾞｹ倒したいのか～！
Do you really want to go that far to act stupid?!
What are you saying, Kintoki?
(坂本)なに言うちょるんじゃ
金時…｡
I was just trying to get those batteries back, if they had them...
(坂本)ﾜｼは ただ その
感電血っちゅうのを➡
預かってもらっちょるなら
返してもらおう…｡
(ﾘｰﾀﾞｰ)ﾌﾌﾌﾌﾌ｡
So you've finally come.
とうとう ここまで やってきたか｡
快援隊よ…｡ んっ？
Pleasure Support Club...
(ﾘｰﾀﾞｰ)あぁ～っ!? お前は…!?
You're...
♪♪～
You're that silver-haired guy!!
お前は あのときの銀髪頭!!
Gin-chan, do you know him?
銀ちゃん 知り合いｱﾙか？
No. I don't really remember him.
いや… よく覚えてないから…｡
ひょっとして
｢ｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟ｣借りたままの ｲｿﾑﾗ君？
Are you Isomura-kun, the guy I never gave back the JUMP to?
I never expected to meet you here!!
こんなところで
また 会えるとはな｡
前回の借り
利子をつけて 返してやるわ！
You're going to pay with interest for what you did to me!!
あ～あ 向こうの皆さん
激しく やる気だよ おい｡
Looks like they're ready for a fierce battle.
どうするんですか？
こんなに たくさん…｡
What are we going to do against so many of them?
Well, we'll manage...
まっ なんとかなるだろう｡
なんとかって あの人数ですよ！
Manage? There's so many of them!
Shut up. I said that we'll manage, so we'll manage.
うるせえなぁ｡
なんとかなるって言ったら➡
なんとか なんだよ…｡
なんですか!?
What's with that baseless confidence?!
その 根拠のない自信は！
お前らは 知らねえだろうけどな➡
You may not know, but Tatsuma Sakamoto is monstrously strong.
坂本 辰馬ってのはよ
化け物みてえに 強え｡
Huh?
攘夷戦争のときにゃ
えらく 有名だったぜ｡
He was pretty famous during the Anti-Foreigner War.
This idiot is strong?
このﾊﾞｶ 強いｱﾙか？
ｱﾊｯ ｱﾊｯ…｡
Yeah. He's really strong. Incredibly strong. He's stupid, though.
あぁ もう 強いも強い｡
めちゃくちゃ強い｡
ﾊﾞｶだけどな｡
ｳｿ～!?
No way!
銀ちゃんより 強いｱﾙか!?
Is that idiot stronger than you?
この ﾊﾞｶが!?
よく聞けよ｡
Listen closely. I never said that idiot was stronger than me.
このﾊﾞｶが ｵﾚより強いなんて
ひと言も 言ってねえよ！
You don't have to keep calling me an idiot. That hurts a lot.
ﾊﾞｶﾊﾞｶ言わんで いいきに！
結構 傷つくぜよ…｡
この ﾊﾞｶが…？
This idiot.
なに のんきに
ｺﾞﾁｬｺﾞﾁｬ言ってやがんだ！
What are you blabbing on about?!
ものども やれ～！
Get them, my minions!!
来た～!!
They're coming!
I guess I have no choice.
こうなったら しかたねえ！
てやぁ～っ!!
ほわちゃ～！
ぐっ…！
ﾌﾌﾌ｡ これからは これじゃと
言うちょるじゃろうが…｡
I said that I'd be using this now.
ありゃりゃ!? ありゃ!?
What's wrong, Tatsuma?!
どうした!? 辰馬！ ていっ！
I dropped my pistols.
ﾋﾟｽﾄﾙ… 落としちゃったぜよ…｡
えぇ～っ!? なんて 役立たず～!!
What?! You're so useless!!
ｱﾊﾊﾊﾊ！
このﾊﾞｶ！ なんとか するｱﾙ!!
Do something, you idiot!
Jeez. Oh well...
ったく しようがねえなぁ！
Here.
ほらよ！
This is...
うっ…｡ これは…｡
Your subordinate said to use it.
お前の部下が 使えってよ！
She probably knew this would happen.
こうなることが
わかってたんじゃねえの!?
Hmm... This goes here... And this goes here...
え～っと… これが こうなって…｡
Why are you dismantling it?!
…って
なに 分解してんですか～!!
Well, when I was holding it...
いや なんか 触っちょったら…｡
He really is an idiot!!
やっぱり ﾊﾞｶだ～!!
Aww man. Leave that idiot alone.
あ～ もう！ ﾊﾞｶは ほっとけ！
(ﾘｰﾀﾞｰ)うぬ～っ…｡
As expected of the man who crushed our hopes. He's pretty strong.
さすがは 我らが
野望を砕いたことのある男…｡
なかなか やるではないか…｡
(幹部)いかがなさいますか？
What should we do?
しかたがない｡ 出すぞ 奥の手を！
はっ！
We have no choice. We're going to use our secret weapon.
Yes...
やれやれ 片づいたぜ…｡
My, my. We've finally cleaned up.
(ﾘｰﾀﾞｰ)ﾜ～ ﾊｯﾊｯﾊｯﾊ～!!
ﾜｯﾊｯﾊｯﾊｯﾊ～！
As I expected of you, Silver-hair. I applaud your ability to corner us this far!
さすがは 銀髪！
我らを ここまで追い詰めるとは
賞賛に値するぞ！
なに 言ってやがる…｡
なんか しゃべり方が➡
What is he talking about?
He sounds pretty arrogant.
やけに 偉そうですよ？
高いところが好きなんて➡
Only monkeys and idiots like high places.
ｻﾙとﾊﾞｶくらいｱﾙ｡
Huh? Did you call me?
えっ？ 呼んだ？
いえ 呼んでません｡
No, we didn't.
(ﾘｰﾀﾞｰ)ﾊ～ ﾊﾊﾊﾊﾊﾊﾊ！
Don't you wonder where your batteries are?
お前たち あの感電血の行方は
気にならないか？
Yes. The batteries are, in a sense,
そう！ 感電血とは…｡
[In a sense, an item that holds enough power to substitute an electric power facility. A true craftsman's piece created through blood, sweat and hard work.]
an item full of so much power that you don't need an electric power facility.
A supreme battery that can only be created by a true craftsman's blood, sweat and hard work!!
Ah. So you do have them after all? If you have them, give them back.
あ～ やっぱ 持ってんだ｡
持ってんなら 返せ～！
No one's going to give anything back just because they're told to.
(ﾘｰﾀﾞｰ)返せ と言われて
素直に返すﾔﾂが いるか～！
Anyway, the fact that we can have a normal conversation means you don't need that megaphone.
つうか
普通に 会話できてるってことは➡
その拡声器って 必要ないんじゃ？
You really are an idiot.
(神楽)やっぱ ﾊﾞｶね！
おっ？
Stupid, stupid, stupid! This is no ordinary megaphone.
ﾊﾞ～ｶ ﾊﾞ～ｶ ﾊﾞ～ｶ！ これは
ただの拡声器じゃねえんだよ!!
Watch this and be amazed!
これ見て 驚け～！ ﾎﾟﾁｯ｡
Click.
♪♪～
あぁ～っ!? あれは ｼﾞｬｽﾀｳｪｲ!?
That's a Justaway!
No, it's not!!
(ﾘｰﾀﾞｰ)違～う！
感電血を 動力に使った➡
It's our battery-powered ultimate weapon, the Justank!!
我らが 最終決戦兵器 ｼﾞｬｽﾀﾝｸだ！
Nothing more, nothing less!!
(ﾘｰﾀﾞｰ)それ以上でも
それ以下でも な～い!!
Come on. That's just a rip-off.
おいおい それ ﾊﾟｸﾘじゃねえか！
訴えられるぞ 工場長に！
The plant manager's going to sue you.
That's copyright infringement.
著作権侵害ですよ！
ﾌﾝ！ 悪の組織が
法律なぞ 守ってられるか！
An evil organization never obeys the laws!!
ﾎﾟﾁｯ｡
Click.
Let's go, Justank!!
(ﾘｰﾀﾞｰ)いくぞ ｼﾞｬｽﾀﾝｸ！
♪♪～
うわぁ～ なんだ～!?
W-What is this?!
うわっ…！
うわぁ～っ!!
I did it!
(坂本)できた！
I finally completed my secret weapon.
とうとう 完成したぜよ｡
ﾜｼの 切り札じゃ…｡
Come on. If you move, I'll fill you with holes.
さぁ 動いたら どてっぱらに…！
あれ？ 誰も おらんきに…｡
Huh? No one's here.
You've been doing that all this time?!
…って
ずっと それ やってたわけ!?
今の状況 わかってんの～!?
Do you understand our current situation?
Wow. That's a big ship.
(坂本)おぉ～
でっかい船じゃのぅ！
船じゃないですから！
敵ですから!!
It's not a ship! It's the enemy!
It's a Justank! It's attacking us!!
ｼﾞｬｽﾀﾝｸですから！
ﾎﾞｸらに 危害 加えてますから!!
♪♪～
うわぁ～!!
なに やってんの～!?
What are you doing?!
What's wrong? Are you running away, Kintoki? You're such a coward.
なんじゃ？ 金時は 逃げるきに？
肝っ玉の ちっちゃいﾔﾂじゃのぅ｡
な～に その引っ掛かる言い方！
ﾁｷﾝﾚｰｽ？ この状況で～!?
What? Why put it so spitefully? Are we playing chicken? At a time like this?
ここは 私に任せるぜよ｡
Leave this to me.
Don't tell me you're going to take on that Justank with a single gun.
まさか 拳銃
１つで あのｼﾞｬｽﾀﾝｸを!?
Take a look at that. It has something on its forehead, right?
(坂本)あれを見るぜよ おでこに
なんか ついてるじゃろう…｡
あれは…｡
(神楽)感電血ｱﾙ｡
That's...
The battery!
弱点 丸出しじゃないですか!?
Its weak spot is out in the open!
(神楽)ご都合ｱﾙよ ご都合｡
That's just convenient. Too convenient.
ご都合 結構｡
(銀時たち)あっ…｡
I'm fine that it's convenient.
If we don't make some cool scenes for me,
ﾜｼのいけてるｼｰﾝも作らにゃ➡
ただのﾊﾞｶの話で終わっちまうぜよ｡
this episode will just be an episode about an idiot.
There!
(坂本)そこじゃ！
(銃声)
[Stand your ground]
(坂本)あれ？
｢ふんばれ｣か…｡
"Stand your ground," huh? You got me there.
こりゃ 一本 取られたようじゃの｡
ｱﾊﾊﾊ ｱﾊﾊ…｡
What is that?! You and your subordinates are all dimwitted!
って なにそれ！ お前の部下も➡
揃って とんち きかせすぎだよ｡
いや とんちっていうより
ﾊﾞｶだろ みんなしてﾊﾞｶだろ｡
No, not dimwitted, but rather idiots! They're all idiots!
いまどき 旗の出るﾋﾟｽﾄﾙなんて➡
It's pretty rare to see a pistol that makes a flag come out nowadays!
お目にかかれないｱﾙよ｡
つか感心してんじゃねえか｡
Don't be impressed by that!
ｱ～ ﾊｯﾊｯﾊｯﾊｯ…｡
万策つきたようだな｡
It looks like you're all out of ideas. And so I'm going to finish you off.
では こちらはとどめといこう｡
♪♪～
あれは!?
What's that?!
ﾈｵｱｰﾑｽﾄﾛﾝｸﾞｻｲｸﾛﾝｼﾞｪｯﾄ
ｱｰﾑｽﾄﾛﾝｸﾞ砲じゃねえか｡
That's the Neo Armstrong Cyclone Jet Armstrong Cannon!
完成度 高っけえな ｵｲ｡
また ﾊﾟｸﾘですか…｡
It's got a very high-quality finish.
Another rip-off, huh?
ﾊﾊﾊﾊﾊ… なんとでも言え｡
Say whatever you like.
ﾈｵｱｰﾑｽﾄﾛﾝｸﾞｻｲｸﾛﾝｼﾞｪｯﾄｱｰﾑｽﾄﾛﾝｸﾞ砲➡
Neo Armstrong Cyclone Jet Armstrong Cannon! Fire!
発射！
(砲撃音)
(銀時たち)うわぁ｡
ｱ～ ﾊｯﾊｯﾊｯﾊｯ…
ここまでのようだな｡
It looks like this is the end for you!
(坂本)ｱﾊﾊﾊﾊ…｡
(坂本)ｱﾊﾊ ｱﾊﾊ…｡
あれは…｡
That's...
♪♪～
(ｵﾍﾟﾚｰﾀｰ)ﾋﾞｰｺﾝ座標 一致
全員無事です｡
Beacon coordinates match. They're all safe.
It seems we made it in time.
(陸奥)どうやら
間に合ったようじゃの｡
ｱﾊﾊﾊﾊ… ｱﾊﾊﾊﾊ…｡
W-What?
なっ なに!?
We are the Pleasure Support Club.
我らは 快援隊｡
坂本 辰馬 率いる ｶﾝﾊﾟﾆｰじゃ｡
The company that Tatsuma Sakamoto leads!
我らの大儀を阻む者は➡
We won't forgive anyone who gets in the way of our business!
何人たりとも許さんぜよ｡
(砲撃音)
(爆発音)
W-W-W-W-What should we do?!
(幹部)どどど どうしましょう!?
反撃だ 撃て 撃てぇ！
Retaliate! Fire, fire!!
(砲撃音)
W-What?!
なっ なに!?
(ﾘｰﾀﾞｰたち)うわぁぁ！
(爆発音)
なんとか間に合ったぜよ 陸奥…｡
You managed to make it in time, Mutsu.
ﾌｯ ｱｲﾂ…｡
That guy...
(陸奥)空… これは➡
Empty?
What is the meaning of this?
いったい どういうことじゃ｡
どこに隠したｱﾙか
本当のこと言うｱﾙ｡
Where did you hide them?! Tell us the truth!
本当に知らないんだ 確かに➡
I-I really don't know! It was there.
そこに あったはずなんだが｡
そんな大事なものほっぽって➡
Leaving something as valuable as that lying around while you all fought outside.
全員 外で戦ってた
って ﾏﾇｹな話ですね｡
That's really dumb.
その間に 誰かが持ち去った…｡
Someone carried them off while we were fighting.
あ…｡
You probably figured it out already. The hint is..."profit!"
もう わかっとるじゃろ｡
ﾋﾝﾄは… 利益ぜよ｡
(青木)急げ なにをｸﾞｽﾞｸﾞｽﾞしている｡
Hurry. Why are you wasting time?
そんなに 急いで
どこ行くつもりだ｡
Where are you going in such a hurry?
(幹部/青木)あっ…｡
You're with the Pleasure Support Club?
(青木)あなたは… 快援隊の…｡
夜のﾄﾞﾗｲﾌﾞか？ それにしちゃあ➡
A night drive? You've got a pretty unsexy companion and truck.
色気のない連れとﾄﾗｯｸじゃねえか｡
いや ご活躍で… なんと
お礼を言っていいのやら｡
Well, how can I ever thank you for your help?
(陸奥)だが おんしゃらの➡
But we didn't find your money or our cargo.
金も ﾜｼらの積み荷も
見つからなかったぜよ｡
それは… いやはや…｡
Well...that's...
Things seem a little too convenient.
ずいぶん できすぎた
話じゃねえか…｡
ｱﾝﾀらの正確な情報の
おかげで事件は解決だ｡
Your correct information led us to solve the case.
だが 金と積み荷だけは➡
But we didn't find the money or the cargo.
どこ 探しても見つからなかった｡
In that case, who benefited the most?
その場合 誰が一番 得をするんだ｡
(陸奥)おんしゃら…
保険 入ってたじゃろ｡
You have insurance, don't you?
えっ あぁ…｡
Huh? Yeah...
(陸奥)とぼけても ﾑﾀﾞぜよ｡
It's no use playing dumb.
(陸奥)金が無くなっても
おまんらには保険がおりる｡
If you lost the money, you'd have the insurance to cover it.
(陸奥)痛くも かゆくもない｡
It doesn't hurt you at all.
仕事を依頼した相手が
つぶれてくれれば なお➡
If the person you hired was crushed, that would be even better.
結構… 口封じにもなるしな｡
It would keep them quiet.
な… なにを｡
W-What?
Everything went according to your plans.
全部 ｱﾝﾀらのｼﾅﾘｵどおり…｡
But you made one mistake in the end.
ただし最後の詰めを
誤ったようだがな…｡
我々を侮辱するつもりか！
Are you insulting us?!
人のよさそうな顔して
やることは大胆だよな｡
It's bold of you to act like a good person.
俺たち 全員
踊らされてたってわけだ｡
That's how you were able to manipulate us all.
け 警察を呼べ｡
いいのか？
C-Call the police.
Are you sure you want to do that? I think you're the one who's going to be arrested.
捕まるのは そっちだと思うぜ｡
Where's your proof?
(青木)証拠は… そこまで
言うなら証拠があるだろう｡
If you've got the guts to accuse me, you've got to have proof!
Proof.
証拠… 証拠ねぇ｡
Proof, huh?
うりゃああああ！
P-President...
しゃ 社長…｡
あ… あぁ…｡
We know everything you're up to, idiot.
全部 お見通しだよ ﾊﾞｰｶ｡
(陸奥)今回は世話になったの｡
Thank you for helping us in this matter.
うぜえから もう ｳﾁに仕事
持ち込むのやめてくれない｡
You're annoying. Don't ever bring work to us again.
ｱｲﾂと一緒にいるとﾊﾞｶが
うつっちまうからよ…｡
I'll catch his stupidity if I stay with him too long.
そういえば 坂本さんは？
Come to think of it, where's Sakamoto-san?
Our boss? Right about now he's...
頭か あんしは今頃…｡
おりょうちゃん 結婚してくれ～｡
Oryo-san, please marry me!
ﾉｰｾﾝｷｭｰ｡
No, thank you!
ﾍﾍﾍ… この厚さなら➡
Judging from the thickness, there's got to be at least three million in here.
300万円は かたいな｡
あ… これ全部 千円札…｡
They're all thousand yen notes.
[Note: Meaning each bill is worth about only $10]
[The moment...]
[has arrived!]
[He's...]
[Making his move!]
[Gin Tama, The Benizakura Arc, starting next episode.]
[Shinsuke Takasugi is finally making his move. The radical Anti-Foreigner group, Kiheitai.]
[What is the Benizakura? An demon sword said to be capable of draining human souls? The greatest danger for the Odd Jobs approaches!!]
＜守らないと 恐ろしいことが→
起こりますよ＞
(ｹｰﾀ)うぅ…｡
ｹｰﾀ…｡
く… 来る…｡
(ｳｨｽﾊﾟｰ)何が来るんです？
お… お母さんのｶﾐﾅﾘが…｡
片づけなさ～い!!